## Fellyph Cintra

Rua do compromisso Marítimo

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/fellyph/

Github: github.com/fellyph

lote b12 3e - Lagos - Portugal

Phone: +351 935997020

Github: github.com/fellyph
WordPress: profiles.wordpress.org/fellyph/

Mail: fellyph.cintra@gmail.com

## Personal Summary

I'm a Web Developer with 14 years of experience. Currently, I'm a Community Manager at rtCamp to activate and educate users on Google projects over the WordPress ecosystem; part of my day, I create video content to inform users and analyze companies' and users' websites to help them solve issues.

My strongest skill is client-side front-end development. My main domains are HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SASS/LESS/PostCSS, Web Component, Angular and React. On the server side, I usually code in Java and PHP. I also use GIT for version control, GruntJS, Gulp, and Webpack for automating tasks and tests with Cypress and Jenkins. I hold a bachelor's degree in Information Systems.

In 2019, I received the title of Google Developer Expert on Web Technologies in recognition of my second passion: supporting local developer communities as a tool of integration and social development.

## Professional Experience

# Community Manager at Google(rtCamp) Remote - 2021 - 2022

As a community manager for the Google AMP plugin, I interacted with developers and non-technical users, helping them achieve their goals. To communicate with these two audiences, I have produced instructional content such as Podcasts, video tutorials, Youtube & Linkedin live streaming, and forums.

To help scale the supporting content, I have produced educational videos (<a href="https://bit.ly/pxroadchannel">https://bit.ly/pxroadchannel</a>) and code examples based on the central issues identified in the official support forum. My work was essential in flagging the users' needs to the development team, reporting issues, and testing fixes. At <a href="main-wp.org">amp-wp.org</a>, I was responsible for creating documentation and blog posts, contacting website owners and plugin developers to feature their projects in the showcase area, and increasing the ecosystem listing by 10%.

#### Front-end Developer at SAU/CAL Remote - 2020 - 2021

As a front-end developer at SAU/CAL, I was responsible for improving the front-end stack of the team, working with cross-team projects to share my knowledge of Gutenberg blocks. I have built websites using reusable blocks, created a design system for site owners to maintain their websites, and kept the visual guideline. Also, I have held Woocommerce websites and helped them to get a better Core Web Vitals score. During my

time at the company, I added tooling to the projects with GitHub actions, husky, to trigger the code check with linters and unit test to help the code review process and code quality.

# Solutions Engineer at Deloitte Digital Dublin - 2018 - 2020

I worked with the public sector for three years at Deloitte Digital. The main objective was to promote a digital transformation across the platform. The work I have done for performance with monitoring, testing, and improving the front-end architecture, resulted in a reduction of over 80% of the total application size.

As a result of my actions, the number of impressions on Google Search increased by 400%. I've introduced new technologies such as EcmaScript Next, Unit Test, and Code Validation. I've been working with the DevOps team to create a new pipeline process on the front-end side. I have worked with C#, MVC4, and Umbraco CMS on the back-end side.

- Led front-end Developers
- Organizing internal Bootcamps, focused on best practices and technologies such as Webpack, Web Components, and ESNext,
- Accessibility champion.
- I supported the UX team to promote the internal design system.

## Fullstack Developer at Inspiration Marketing Dublin - 2016 - 2017

Working at Inspiration Marketing, I created the new modular WordPress template to speed up the internal process of developing new client's websites Using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, SASS, Webpack, Babel, EcmaScript2015, and AMP. I created plugins using AngularJS and worked closely with the SEO team to improve the search performance of the websites.

- Updating the agency's workflow using Progressive Web Apps, Webpack, EcmaScript2015 AngularJS, and GitHub
- Co-creating new products for the clients
- Organizing internal training every month
- Promoting pair programing to share knowledge among the team

### Front-End Developer at Elo7 Sao Paulo - 2014 - 2016

In my first year in Elo7, I was tasked with developing the web mobile version of the marketplace. My team's focus was to make a fast and light mobile version. We worked with HTML5, SASS, JavaScript, GruntJS, nodeJS, tests with RSpec, and Back-end with Java. After this, we migrated to the Java framework: Struts to vRaptor.

- For two years, I worked with pair programming, AMD, TDD, Acceptance tests(RSpec), A/B tests.
- I organized an internal HackDay monthly with the whole engineering team.

#### Technical leader at BlackBerry Sao Paulo - 2013 - 2014

At Blackberry my main responsibility was to teach and guide 10 students from São Paulo University(USP) and develop mobile applications using HTML5, JavaScript, CSS3, SASS, and AngularJS.

- Throughout this time I managed a team of ten web developers
- Provided support to other partners to migrate their applications to BlackBerry OS
- Created Applications using PhoneGap and AngularJS.

#### Front-end Developer at UOL Sao Paulo - 2012 - 2013

My responsibility was to develop and maintain the "Blogosfera" a WordPress multisite with 60 different blogs. Inside UOL we worked with huge cross-browser support and the basic work spec used HTML, JavaScript, iQuery, Velocity, and PHP.

- I created a theme using Velocity, with this change we increased the speed of the platform over 60%.
- I was also responsible for the comments application using Javascript vanilla.

#### Web Developer at EverMedia Sao Paulo - 2011 - 2012

My Work there consisted of creating web publicity campaigns using: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP and WordPress.

#### Front-end Developer at Cherry Plus Sao Paulo - 2009 - 2011

During my period working in Cherryplus, I dedicated myself to online campaigns, fanpages, blogs and websites for different fashion companies. I used some technologies such as: HTML5, LESS, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, ActionScript, PHP and WordPress.

Previous experiences on my Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/fellyph/

## Technical Skill Set

- JavaScript(ES5/ES6)
- Web components
- Angular
- ReactJS
- Node
- HTML5/CSS3
- · SASS/LESS
- PostCSS
- Progressive Web Apps
- AMP
- jQuery
- Git
- Grunt, Gulp and Webpack
- Java

- PHP
- WordPress
- Agile

### Education

**2002-2007** Graduate in Information System at - Faculdade Integrada do Recife(Brazil)

### Awards

2019/2022 - Google Developer expert for web technologies

### Community Open Source

#### WordPress

I have been contributing with the WordPress project for more than ten years:

- WordCamp organizer, three conferences in two continents South America(2014/2015) and Europe(2019).
- Translating WordPress with over 5000 strings for plugins with more than 2.5 million installations and presenting talks in more than 20 WordCamps around the globe.
- At the support forum, I have Answered over 600 topics.
- Recently, I published video tutorials about the new WordPress features at learn.wordpress.org.

#### profiles.wordpress.org/fellyph/

#### Google Developer Expert

Since 2019, as a Google developer expert, I have posted more than 200 video tutorials, Livestream, and podcasts, spoken at 12 conferences, and run 15 workshops. That content is focused on educating developers about web standards, performance, CSS, accessibility, Progressive Web Apps, and SEO. I have interacted with different Google products testing, raising issues on GitHub, and talking with the respective developer team to bring feedback about their products. I have ten recognized activities with an impact on products and the community.

https://developers.google.com/community/experts/directory/profile/profile
-fellyph-cintra

#### Interests

in Swimming, running, photography, surfing, traveling and cooking.